SHUBHAM GOYAL

DATA SCIENTIST

🗷 shubhamgoyal769@gmail.com 📞 8700664182 👂 Noida,India in shubham-goyal-0946b7127 🕠 shubham769

SUMMARY

Shubham Goyal is a Data Scientist at Knoldus Inc. With this, he is an artificial intelligence researcher, interested in doing research on different domain problems and a regular contributor to society through blogs and webinars in machine learning and artificial intelligence.

EDUCATION

Lovely Professional University

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2019

B.Tech

Computer Science & Engineering

Major - Data Science

Apr. 2013 - Mar. 2015

Higher Secondary Education

May 2012 - May 2013

Bohra Public School High School Education

Bohra Public School

EMPLOYMENT

Knoldus Inc, Data Scientist, Noida

July 2019 - Current

Software Consultant Trainee, Noida, India

Jan. 2019 - June 2019

HandyKarts web services,

Apr. 2017 -

Machine Learning Engineer, Punjab, India

Oct. 2018

SKILLS

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE: Data Analysis,

Machine Learning, Deep Learning,

Natural Language Processing, Statistics, Image Processing, Computer Vision

PROGRAMMING: Python, R, SQL, NoSQL, Scala, C++, Pyspark TOOLS & LIBRARIES: Anaconda, Tableau, MS-Excel, Keras, Scikit-Learn, NLTK, Matplotllib, Seaborn, Tensorflow, Open CV, PyTorch, Knime, Spark MLlib, Flask, GCP, AWS, Docker, mlflow

VOLUNTEERING

Towards Data Science, Writer Medium

Aug. 2019 - Current

June

2019

Jan. 2020 -

Current

Towards Data Science provides a platform for thousands of people to exchange ideas and to expand our understanding of data science.

PUBLICATIONS

Prediction on Diabetes Patient's Hospital Readmission Rates

3rd International Conference On Advanced Informatics For Computing Research, Shimla

Journal - ACM

Novel XGBoost Tuned Machine Learning **Model for Software Bug Prediction**

ICIEM - 2020: International Conference on Intelligent Engineering and Management, London, UK Journel - Springer, IEEE

PROJECTS

Knoldus forecasting Platform

May 2020 - Current

- The goal of the project is to create a collaborative platform for time series analysis and forecasting between data engineers and data scientists with help of Knime.
- · A Guided Analytic platform is created, where user can do data preparation, data aggregation, data visualisations and can choose algorithm based on time series component's analysis
- · Further, after forecasting, platform also gave a collaboration between different hierarchy levels of supply chain management or decision makers and take feedback back to the platform about forecasting performance.

Hpe Analytics

Jan. 2020 - May 2020

- · Failure handling was not precise due to the lack of information on the usage trend. So, we made a common portal for the customers where they can take advantage of different predictive features for all kind of HPE storage
- Prediction on when the storage might go out of space when CPU utilization might go at peak or to summarise prediction on when a disaster will happen, helps the users avoid various loses.

Earthquake Prediction

Apr. 2019 - May 2019

- The goal of this project is to use seismic signals to predict the timing of laboratory earthquakes. The data comes from a well-known experimental set-up used to study earthquake physics. The acoustic_data input signal is used to predict the time remaining before the next laboratory earthquake time_to_failure.
- · The training data was a single, continuous segment of experimental data from the Laboratory. Implemented Simple XGB Regressor to predict the correct output with a mean absolute error of 2.43635 and the Solution was awarded a silver medal on Kaggle.

Trailblazer

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- · Technology Stack: Scala, Lagom, Kafka, Cassandra, Prometheus, Grafana, Docker, Kubernetes
- Developed an application that is capable to consume and process real-time temperature data collected via sensors to provide monitoring, alerting, and visualization over it.
- Features: 1. Real-time stream data processing. 2. Persist data in the persistent store(Event Sourcing and CQRS). 3. View stored data. 4. Integrated with another service(Notification Service) to generate alerts when there is a spike in the temperature

ACHIEVEMENTS

Knime certified. Knime

June 2020

Certified with knime level 1- level 4 certifications

LANL Earthquake Prediction, Kaggle Won silver medal and top 2% spot

May 2019

International Conference on Advanced Informatics for Computing Research , ICAICR

June 2019

Successfully presented my research paper at International Conference